(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-06T22:32:18.586714",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
本日は、ReGLOSS 3D LIVE「Reach the top」にお越しいただき、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for attending today's ReGLOSS 3D LIVE "Reach the top".
皆様に本公演の注意事項を申し上げます。
We would like to inform you of the guidelines for this performance.
携帯電話の電源はお切りせずに、パソコン、タブレットなどとの複数窓でのご視聴をおすすめしております。
Please keep your mobile phones on and view across multiple windows with PCs, tablets, etc.
公演中のおしゃべりは大歓迎です！ぜひコメントして本公演を一緒に盛り上げてください。
Chatting during the performance is very welcome! Please comment and liven up the show together.
公演中の写真撮影も大歓迎です！たくさんスクショしてハッシュタグ「#ReGLOSS3Dライブ」でポストしてください。
Taking photos during the performance is also very welcome! Take plenty of screenshots and post with the hashtag #ReGLOSS3DLive.
二十歳以上の方に限り、ご自宅内での喫煙、飲酒も可となっております。思う存分お楽しみください。
For those 20 and over, smoking and drinking at home are also permitted. Please enjoy to your heart's content.
本公演の後にメンバーシップ限定のライブがございます。ぜひメンバーシップへの参加をお願いいたします。
There will be a membership-exclusive live stream after this performance. Please consider joining the membership.
それでは、開演までしばらくお待ちください！
Well then, please wait a moment until the show starts!
皆様、本日はReGLOSS 3Dライブ「Reach the top」にお越しいただき誠にありがとうございます。
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to the ReGLOSS 3D Live "Reach the Top" today.
皆様に本公演の注意事項を申し上げます。
We would like to inform you of the precautions for this performance.
携帯電話の電源は切らずに、ええ！？
Please keep your mobile phones powered on—what?!
パソコン、タブレットなどでの複数窓での視聴、お辞めください！
Please refrain from watching with multiple windows on PCs or tablets!
500窓！？ 500窓！？えっ？
500 windows?! 500 windows?! What?
公演中のおしゃべりは大歓迎です！
Chatting during the performance is very welcome!
コメントして本公演を一緒に盛り上げてください！
Please comment and hype up this performance together with us!
公演中の写真撮影も大歓迎です！
Taking photos during the performance is also very welcome!
たくさん写真撮ってたくさん使って、
Take lots of photos, use them a lot,
ハッシュタグ「ReGLOSS 3Dライブ」でポストしてください！あと「青くんかっこいい」とも言ってください！イエーイ！
and post them with the hashtag "#ReGLOSS3Dlive"! And also say "Ao-kun is cool"! Yay!
二十歳以上の方に限り、ご自宅内での喫煙、飲酒も可となっております！思う存分お楽しみください！
Limited to those 20 and older, smoking and drinking alcohol at home are also permitted! Please enjoy to your heart's content!
そして、本公演の後にメンバーシップ限定のライブがございます！
And after this performance, there will be a membership-exclusive live stream!
ぜひメンバーシップへの参加をお願いいたします！
We kindly ask you to join the membership!
それでは、開演までしばらくお待ちください！
Now then, please wait a moment until the show begins!
ReGLOSS!
行くよ！
Let's go!
いつか心にもない軽口で
With thoughtless words I never meant,
みだりに君を怒らせてしまったね
I carelessly made you mad, didn't I?
「ごめんね」さえ言い出せなかった
I couldn't even bring myself to say "I'm sorry".
この心臓の音がうるさくて
The beating of my heart was so loud,
いつだってこれ以上は止めにしようと
Always thinking "Let's put an end to this",
組み上げてきた積み木を手放した
I let go of the building blocks I stacked up.
鼓動に揺れた指先に触れて崩れてしまう前にとそう
Before my trembling fingertips touch and collapse it, yes.
悩みの種はいつでも誰かのことと
The seeds of worry are always about someone else,
明日のことと未来のことばかりだね
About tomorrow, and about the future.
考えるほど駆け足で
The more I think, the faster I run,
脈打つリズムもっと上手にもっと綺麗に
Beating rhythm, more skillfully, more cleanly.
刻んだら足がすくんでしまっても声が震えても
If I carve it, even if my legs freeze or voice shakes,
お構いなし心は置き去りのままで加速していくビート
Never mind, leaving my heart behind, the beat accelerates.
まだ準備も出来ていないのに
Even though I'm not ready yet,
右向け右の通りにはみださないように揃えられた
Kept in line so as not to step out of "right face",
僕を残したままで加速する日々よ
Leaving me behind as the days accelerate.
どんな風に歩いていたっけどんな僕が僕だったっけ
How was I walking? What kind of self was I?
ずっと遠くに見えてたずっと先の未来は
The future far ahead that seemed so distant,
ずっと近くに来ていたずっとずっと
Has come so close, always, always.
本当に大事なことはいつでも教えてくれない
What's truly important is never taught to us anytime.
これからのこと肝心なところ今も考えれば考えるほど
Things from now on, the crucial parts, the more I think now,
分からなくてもっと格好良くてもっと胸張って
The less I understand, I want to be cooler, chest out more.
進めれば足がすくんでしまっても声が震えても
If I advance, even if my legs freeze or voice shakes,
お構いなし心は置き去りのままで加速していくビート
Never mind, leaving my heart behind, the beat accelerates.
張り裂けてしまいそうだよ喉につかえた「ごめんね」
It feels like it's going to burst, "I'm sorry" stuck in my throat.
揺れ動く指先いつも思えばこの心の奥が痛いほど
Swaying fingertips, whenever I think, deep in my heart, so much it hurts,
脈打つのはかけがえのないものに愛すべきものに触れた瞬間ばかりだ
It only beats when I touch something irreplaceable, something lovable.
きっと飛び跳ねる心臓が鳴らした音は
Surely, the sound made by my leaping heart
僕にとって本当に大切なものを教えてくれてんだずっと
Has always been teaching me what is truly precious to me.
いつだって誰かに貼られた「らしさ」はいらない
I don't need the "likeness" slapped on me by anyone ever.
どこまでもおしゃれ僕のハートビート誰でもない
Fashionable all the way, my heartbeat, nobody else's.
自己誇らしく鳴らし響き渡らせそうな心で鳴らす世界で一つの証さ
Ringing with self-pride, making it echo with a heart ready to resound, the one and only proof.
ずっと遠くに見えてたずっと先の未来は
The future far ahead that seemed so distant,
ずっと近くに来ていたずっとずっと前から
Has come so close, from long, long ago.
僕がずっと探していたものはずっと近くにあったんだ
What I've been searching for all along was right beside me.
ずっとずっとこれは始まりの合図だ
Always, always, this is the signal of the beginning.
いつか心にもない軽口でみだりに君を怒らせてしまったね
With thoughtless words I never meant, I carelessly made you mad.
「ごめんね」さえ言い出せなかったこの心臓の音がうるさくて
I couldn't even say "I'm sorry", the beating of my heart was so loud.
いつだってこれ以上は止めにしようと組み上げてきた積み木を手放した
Always thinking "Let's put an end to this", I let go of the stacked blocks.
鼓動に揺れた指先に触れて崩れてしまう前にとそう
Before my trembling fingertips touch and collapse it, yes.
悩みの種はいつでも誰かのことと明日のことと未来のことばかりだね
The seeds of worry are always about someone else, tomorrow, and the future.
考えるほど駆け足で脈打つリズムもっと上手にもっと綺麗に
The more I think, running fast, the beating rhythm, more skillfully, more cleanly.
刻んだら足がすくんでしまっても声が震えてもお構いなし
If I carve it, even if my legs freeze or voice shakes, never mind.
心は置き去りのままで加速していくビートまだ準備も出来ていないのに
Leaving my heart behind, the beat accelerates, even though I'm not ready yet.
右向け右の通りにはみださないように揃えられた僕を残したままで
Kept in line so as not to step out of "right face", leaving me behind.
加速する日々よどんな風に歩いていたっけどんな僕が僕だったっけ
The accelerating days, how was I walking? What kind of self was I?
ずっと遠くに見えてたずっと先の未来はずっと近くに来ていた
The future far ahead that seemed so distant has come so close.
シンメトリー
[Title: Symmetry]
ざめく街の喧騒
The bustling noise of the streets,
掻き消すように弦を弾いて
strumming the strings to drown it out.
一心不乱に叫ぶ午後
An afternoon screaming with single-minded devotion,
割れた爪を眺め 憂い暇もないよ
gazing at broken nails, I have no time to grieve.
時の流れに呑み込まれたっていい
It's fine if I was swallowed by the flow of time,
立ち塞がる壁に 真っ向から迎え撃とう
meeting the towering wall head-on to fight back.
パッと見まごう落書き
A fleeting glance at graffiti,
磨き続ければ masterpiece
keep polishing it into a masterpiece.
登り詰めてく頂
Climbing up to the summit,
努力だけは裏切らない
hard work never betrays you.
撒いてる点と線
Scattering dots and lines,
インスパイア 扇動的？
inspired, provocative?
多少強引でもご愛嬌
Even if a bit forceful, it's endearing.
じっと見つめて
Staring intently,
駆け抜けてく戦慄の夜
running through the thrilling night.
恋焦がれて咲き乱れて
Yearning and blooming in disarray,
失いかけた夢の続きを紡いでいこう
let's weave together the continuation of a lost dream.
渇いた世界を満たしてメロディ
Filling the thirsty world with melody,
give your love 一心同体
give your love, body and soul as one.
(okay!!)
キミと織り重なるシンメトリー
Symmetry intertwining with you,
手繰り寄せる朝日のほうへ
toward the beckoning morning sun.
ほんの微妙なニュアンスの違い
A subtle difference in nuance,
絶妙なバランスの塩梅で
with a superb balance and seasoning.
すべての歯車たちは
All the gears
巧妙に噛み合っている
are meshing intricately.
数学より緻密なアーカイブ
An archive more precise than mathematics,
巻き込む偏ったパラダイム
a biased paradigm wrapping around.
いつも隣り合わせ dead or alive
Always side by side, dead or alive,
これもきっと誰かの another life
this too is surely someone else's another life.
近未来も新時代も信じない
I don't believe in the near future or new era,
今だけを切り開くよ
I'll carve open the present alone.
迫る終焉の足音
The approaching footsteps of the end,
願いごたちは僅か灯る
wishes are faintly lit.
始まりまであと一歩
One step until the beginning,
息を潜めて
holding my breath.
静寂を切り裂いて 空へ翼羽ばたかせて
Tearing through the silence, spreading wings toward the sky,
待ち望む結末に 瞬きすらできないよ
I can't even blink at the awaited conclusion.
どんな過去も傷もカタストロフィ
Any past or wound is a catastrophe,
believe in yourself 飛び越える
believe in yourself, jumping over.
(okay!!)
真っ新な夜明けに秘めた想い
Feelings hidden in a brand-new dawn,
もう後戻りはしない
there's no turning back now.
駆け抜けてく戦慄の夜
Running through the thrilling night,
恋焦がれて咲き乱れて
yearning and blooming in disarray,
失いかけた夢の続きを紡いでいこう
let's weave together the continuation of a lost dream.
渇いた世界を満たしてメロディ
Filling the thirsty world with melody,
give your love 一心同体
give your love, body and soul as one.
(okay!!)
キミと織り重なるシンメトリー
Symmetry intertwining with you,
手繰り寄せる朝日のほうへ
toward the beckoning morning sun.
イェーイ！
Yeah!
お疲れ様でした！
Great job, everyone!
いやー緊張した！
Man, I was so nervous!
でもトレンド1位だって！
But we got #1 on trending!
本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much!
トレンド1位だって！
Trend #1!
みんなのおかげだよ、ありがとう！
Thanks to everyone, thank you!
やるぞやるぞって意気込んでさ、自分で飲んでおいで
We were all pumped up, drinking so much water
お腹がタプタプになるやん！
your tummy gets all squishy!
はい、そういうことでございまして
Yes, so with that being said,
本日は本当にありがとうございました！
thank you all so much for today!
おジャ魔女が集まったから
Since the troublemakers have gathered,
いつものやついきますか！
shall we do our usual thing?
リーチザトップ！
Reach the Top!
ウィアー、リーダーズ！
We are, ReGLOSS!
もう一回もう一回！
One more time, one more time!
リーチザトップ！ウィアー、リーダーズ！
Reach the Top! We are, ReGLOSS!
かわいい女の子かと思った？じゃじゃーん、青くんでした！
Did you think I was a cute girl? Ta-da, it's Ao-kun!
ホロライブデバイスReGLOSSの漫画から飛び出してきた！
The manga of Hololive Device ReGLOSS leaped out!
かわいい！ポジティブ！ジニアス！
Cute! Positive! Genius!
ホロライブデバイスReGLOSSの一条莉々華だよ！
It's Hololive Device ReGLOSS's Ichijo Ririka!
ホロライブデバイスReGLOSSの儒烏風亭らでん！
Hololive Device ReGLOSS's Juufuutei Raden!
とと、じゅて、じゅものはぜーんぶ見習いじゅて
Toto, jutte, the spells are all apprentice spells!
あ、ラネでございまーす！よっしゃー！
Ah, lane for you! Let's go!
そして
And then,
はい、ぷんぷんぷん！
Hey, punpunpun!
ほらでばちかてばちさりごろつのパンチよ
Look at that, hitting punch, the punch is coming!
届き始めるぜ
It's starting to reach you!
よっしゃ！っていうことでに、じこじょーかいも終わりましたが。
Alright! With that said, self-introductions are over.
うん！
Yeah!
みんな、3Dだー！
Everyone, we're in 3D!
待って待って待って待って、みんな。
Wait, wait, wait, wait, everyone.
2曲歌ったわけですけど
We sang two songs, but
歌った！
We sang!
待って、踊ったじゃん！
Wait, we danced too!
踊った、踊った！
We danced, we danced!
かけて、もしかしてそのふりって
Wait, could that pose be...
はっ！もしかして？もしかして、だれが？
Ha! Could it be? Could it be, who?
だれですか？
Who is it?
じちゃ、じどきはじめがえーと、シュカハートビートとシンメトリー、えー、サビの振り付け担当しましたー！
I was in charge of the choreography for "Shunkan Heartbeat" and "Symmetry"!
すっげー！すっげー！すごい！すごい！にばんちょう！あ、ポディポディ。あ、ポディポディポディポディ。えーということで、はい。
Awesome! Amazing! Nibancho! Podi podi.
そして、グロッサのみんな、アルバム予約してくれたかなー！
And ReGLOSS everyone, have you pre-ordered the album?
今回のセットリスト、セットリストにはなんと11月リリースのアースアルバム、リーグロスの全楽曲7曲をお披露目しまーす！
This setlist features all 7 tracks from ReGLOSS's first album releasing in November!
半分くらいはね、初おひろめの曲なので、楽しみにしれてください！
About half of them are being performed for the first time, so look forward to it!
え、早速瞬間ハートビートとシンメトリーをおひろめしましたが、どうだったかなー？
We just debuted "Shunkan Heartbeat" and "Symmetry"—how was it?
みんな、すごいコメントが！ねぇ、すごいいえーい！たくさんコメントしてくれてるねぇ、本当だ！ありがとうございます！
Everyone's leaving such great comments! Yay! Thank you so much!
でもね、まだまだ楽しいこともりだくさん！これからもいっぱい歌っていくので、みんないっぱい楽しんでってくださーい！
There's still plenty of fun to come! We'll keep singing a lot, so please enjoy!
楽しんでってね！
Enjoy yourselves!
もうしょうがないなよしほい
Well, can't be helped. Here we go.
同じ未来を見ていた あの夢手に入れたい
We wanted to see the same future, want to make that dream ours.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo
Run, go, with our respective unique hearts!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
Sprouting in a pitch-dark place wherever I looked,
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
My gaze was captured by a tiny, faint hope.
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my trembling, anxious heart just right,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I mustered up a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up" and moving forward.
苦しいときも、もうわたしはひとりじゃないからだからもっと夢追いかけたい ワクワク止まらない
Even in tough times, I'm not alone anymore, so I want to chase my dreams even more, my excitement won't stop.
想像越えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that surpasses imagination.
アクセスしてみたい 後悔なんてそうさせない それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo
I want to access it, no room for regrets—run, go, with our respective unique hearts!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは 見たことのない光をリアルに届けるよ
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky deliver unseen light into reality.
いつも聴こえるエールをここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers we always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
I find myself wanting to search for a new light.
君の笑顔は保存して進む 悲しいときにみかえる力が湧くから
Moving forward while saving your smiles, they give me strength when I'm sad.
胸を張って夢追いかけたい 奇跡のストーリー 一緒に作ろう終わらない夢を
With my head held high, I want to chase dreams, a miraculous story, let's create an endless dream together.
誰一人欠かせない愛が舞い立ったこの世界 それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
In this world where love dances without a single person missing, let's color it with our respective unique hearts.
悲しいときも寂しいときも信じ合えるものがある 忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい 終わらない世界に溢れ出る笑顔達 憧れの舞台立たしたいらしく輝きたい
Whether sad or lonely, we have something we can believe in, I want to keep ringing this heartbeat without forgetting, overflowing smiles in an endless world, I want to stand on the admired stage and shine brightly.
ときに涙してまた笑い合いたい
Sometimes I want to cry and laugh together again.
同じ未来を見ていた あの夢手に入れたい 踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
We wanted to see the same future, want to make that dream ours, let's take a miraculous step forward.
息切らして夢追いかけたい ワクワク止まらない 想像越えてく世界見せてあげる
Out of breath, I want to chase dreams, excitement won't stop, I'll show you a world beyond imagination.
アクセスしてみたい？ 後悔なんてここにない
Want to try accessing? There are no regrets here.
それぞれ違ったココロで作るworld 終わらない夢を 誰一人欠かせない愛がまったこの世界
Building a world with respective unique hearts, an endless dream, in this world where no single person's love is missing.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo 仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは 見たことのない光をリアルに届けるよ
Run, go, with respective unique hearts, the dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky deliver unseen light into reality.
いつも聴こえるエールをここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers we always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ 君の笑顔は保存して進む 悲しいときにみかえるよ
I want to search for new light, moving forward saving your smiles, I'll look back at them when I'm sad.
同じ未来を見ていたい
Wanting to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
wanting that dream in our hands.
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
Sprouting in places that were pitch black wherever I looked,
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
my eyes were stolen by just a tiny bit of hope.
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my wavering, anxious heart just right,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I mustered up just a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting words of giving up to press onward—
苦しいときも、もう私はひとりじゃないから
even in painful times, I'm no longer alone.
だからもっと夢追いかけたいワクワク止まらない
That's why I want to chase my dreams more, my excitement never stops.
想像越えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that surpasses imagination.
アクセスしてみたい後悔なんてそうさせない
Try accessing it, I won't let you have any regrets.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go
Run with each of our different hearts, go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
Those dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光を現実に届けるよ
deliver an unprecedented light to reality.
いつも聴こえるエールはここにキャプチャーして
Capture the cheers we always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
and I'll want to search for brand new lights once more.
君の笑顔は保存して進む
Saving your smile as I press forward,
悲しいときに見返すよ力が湧くから
I'll look back at it when I'm sad, because it gives me strength.
胸を張って夢追いかけたい奇跡の物語
Holding my head high, I want to chase my dream in this miraculous story.
一緒に作ろう終わらない夢を
Let's create an endless dream together.
誰一人欠かせない愛が舞ったこの世界
This world danced with a love where not a single person is missing.
それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
Colorful with each of our different hearts,
悲しいときも寂しいときも
whether in sad times or lonely times,
信じ合えるものがある
we have something we can believe in together.
忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
Without forgetting, I want to keep ringing this heartbeat.
終わらない世界に溢れ出すよ笑顔達
Overflowing into an endless world, smiles abound.
憧れの舞台立ちたいらしく輝きたい
Standing on the stage of my yearnings, shining brightly,
3Dライブ見に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to see my 3D live!
この景色を見られたのは読者とプロースターがいてくれたから
Being able to see this view is thanks to all the readers and Pro-stars being here.
出会ってくれてありがとう
Thank you for meeting me.
愛してるよ！
I love you!
みんなで行こう僕たちの夢
Let's all go towards our dreams,
ほら広がる世界の先へ
look, beyond the expanding world.
手をかざして未来へ向かう
Holding our hands up toward the future,
素敵な何かが待ってる
something wonderful is waiting.
鳴らししてリンリンドン
Ringing ding-ding-dong,
手のひらいっぱいの
with a palmful of
希望を胸に扉開けて
hope in our hearts, open the door.
ミュージアム ミュージアム かけがえのない
Museum, museum, an irreplaceable
大切な未来をつなぐひみつミュージアム
secret museum connecting our precious future.
ファンタジー ファンタジー 足りないのは何？
Fantasy, fantasy, what's missing?
一緒に見つけようよキミにもできるはずさ
Let's find it together, you can do it too.
みんなでつなぐ僕たちの夢
Connecting our dreams together,
ほら広がる心の中へ
look, deep within our expanding hearts.
笑い合えば自信も持てる
If we laugh together we can gain confidence,
素敵な冒険が待ってるよ
a wonderful adventure awaits.
鳴らししてリンリンドン
Ringing ding-ding-dong,
手のひらいっぱいの
with a palmful of
希望を胸に扉開けて
hope in our hearts, open the door.
ミュージアム ミュージアム かけがえのない
Museum, museum, an irreplaceable
大切な未来をつなぐひみつミュージアム
secret museum connecting our precious future.
ファンタジー ファンタジー 足りないのは何？
Fantasy, fantasy, what's missing?
一緒に見つけようよキミにもできるはずさ
Let's find it together, you can do it too.
みんなでつなぐ僕たちの夢
Connecting our dreams together,
ほら広がる心の中へ
look, deep within our expanding hearts.
笑い合えば自信も持てる
If we laugh together we can gain confidence,
素敵な冒険が待ってるよ
a wonderful adventure awaits.
鳴らししてリンリンドン
Ringing ding-ding-dong,
手のひらいっぱいの
with a palmful of
希望を胸に扉開けて
hope in our hearts, open the door.
ミュージアム ミュージアム かけがえのない
Museum, museum, an irreplaceable
大切な未来をつなぐひみつミュージアム
secret museum connecting our precious future.
鳴らししてリンリンドン
Ringing ding-ding-dong,
手のひらいっぱいの
with a palmful of
希望を胸に扉開けて
hope in our hearts, open the door.
ミュージアム ミュージアム かけがえのない
Museum, museum, an irreplaceable
大切な未来をつなぐひみつミュージアム
secret museum connecting our precious future.
ファンタジー ファンタジー 足りないのは何？
Fantasy, fantasy, what's missing?
一緒に見つけようよキミにもできるはずさ
Let's find it together, you can do it too.
ファンタジー ファンタジー 足りないのは何？
Fantasy, fantasy, what's missing?
一緒に見つけようよキミにもできるはずさ
Let's find it together, you can do it too.
鳴らししてリンリンドン
Ringing ding-ding-dong,
手のひらいっぱいの
with a palmful of
希望を胸に扉開けて
hope in our hearts, open the door.
ミュージアム ミュージアム かけがえのない
Museum, museum, an irreplaceable
大切な未来をつなぐひみつミュージアム
secret museum connecting our precious future.
ファンタジー ファンタジー 足りないのは何？
Fantasy, fantasy, what's missing?
一緒に見つけようよキミにもできるはずさ
Let's find it together, you can do it too.
ファンタジー ファンタジー 足りないのは何？
Fantasy, fantasy, what's missing?
一緒に見つけようよキミにもできるはずさ
Let's find it together, you can do it too.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
え？
Huh?
何々何々？
What, what?
ここどこ？
Where is this?
え、ちょ、なんか手足縛られてんだけど！
Wait, my hands and feet are tied up!
どういうこと？ 何の状況なのこれ？
What is the meaning of this? What's going on?
うわ！ なんかめちゃくちゃでっかいの出てきた！
Whoa! Something huge just appeared!
なんかみんな3Dライブでさ、歌ったり踊ったりさ、華やかな感じだったけど、リリカはさ…
Everyone else had such glamorous 3D lives singing and dancing, but Lirika...
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
はぁ、聞こえる。
Yes, I can hear you.
なんか聞き覚えのある声がするわ。なんだ？
That voice sounds familiar. Who is that?
1年ぶりのデスゲーム会場へようこそ。
Welcome to the death game venue for the first time in a year.
これデスゲームかー！
This is a death game?!
今からあなたには格付けに挑戦してもらいます。
From now on, you will take on a ranking challenge.
格付け？
Ranking?
1年の間にすっかりB級タレントがついてしまって、味音痴だと思われているあなたにチャンスを与えてあげましょう。
Let's give you a chance since you've picked up B-list vibes over the year and everyone thinks you have no palate.
いやいやいやいや、リリカは味音痴ではない！
No, no, no, no! Lirika is not bad at tasting!
安い、早い、美味いを追求した結果があれなだけですから、味はもうめちゃめちゃ分かりますから！
That's just the result of pursuing cheap, fast, and delicious food! I know my tastes very well!
ナメないでもらっていいですか？
Don't underestimate me!
そうですか。
Is that so?
これから目隠しをした状態で、「牛肉」の格付けに挑戦。
From now on, you will take on the beef ranking challenge blindfolded.
A・B・Cの肉を食べて値段順に格付けできたらクリア
Eat meats A, B, and C and rank them by price to clear.
なるほど！ え、手足も縛られた状態で、目隠しもしてもらえるご褒美企画ってこと？ 夢が叶った！
I see! Wait, a reward project where my hands and feet are tied and I'm blindfolded? My dream came true!
何回食べてもらうのは、牛ヒレ肉のステーキ？
What you'll eat is beef tenderloin steak?
1つは200g 12,000円の高級ステーキ。
One is a 200g luxury steak worth 12,000 yen.
もう1つは200g 3,000円のステーキ。
Another is a 200g steak worth 3,000 yen.
そしてもう1つは900円のポークステーキ。つまり豚肉です。
And another is a 900 yen pork steak. In other words, pork.
豚肉！？
Pork?!
さすがに豚肉と…ね、さすがに豚肉と牛肉の違いぐらい分かると思うんだけどな。
Seriously, pork... I mean, surely I can tell the difference between pork and beef.
え、てかさ、1万円を超えるヒレ肉って言ってて？ なんて幸せなんだ！ 早く食べたい！
Wait, did you say tenderloin over 10,000 yen? How blissful! I want to eat it soon!
制限時間は3分。
The time limit is 3 minutes.
まもなくスタートするので目隠し付けちゃいましょうか。
It's about to start, so let's put the blindfold on.
え？ 待って、もうタイマー始まってんの？
Eh? Wait, has the timer already started?
早く！ 早く目隠しして！ 早く！ うあ、うわあ、前が見えなくなった！
Hurry! Put the blindfold on fast! Hurry! Whoa, I can't see ahead!
怖い。結構怖いな手足縛られて。
It's scary. Having my hands and feet tied is pretty scary.
え、でもちょっと待って。3分だよね？ 早く持ってきて！
Wait, it's 3 minutes, right? Hurry and bring it over!
1個目。
First one.
あ、お、ん。ん？ん、美味しい！なんだこれ？ん？なんかピリッとする。
Ah, oh, hmm. Hm? Mm, delicious! What is this? Hm? It has a slight spicy kick.
うーん、でもこれ牛肉かな？
Hmm, but is this beef?
なんかね、ビーフジャーキーの味するわ。めちゃめちゃ美味しい！
It kind of tastes like beef jerky. Super delicious!
え、次のもください！
Um, give me the next one too!
B。お。うーん。
B. Oh. Hmm.
やばい。え？ これAとB同じですよ？ え、違うのもしかして？
Oh no. Eh? Are A and B the same? Wait, are they different?
やばい。え、なんか両方とも…
Oh no. Wait, both of them...
もうダメかもリリカ！
Lirika might be done for!
じゃあCも。うん。C。え？
Then C too. Yeah. C. Eh?
ん？ん？ん？
Hm? Hm? Hm?
Cはなんか家でよく食べる味がする。待ってこれ豚だわ！
C tastes like something I often eat at home. Wait, this is pork!
これ絶対豚！Cは豚だわ！
This is definitely pork! C is pork!
ちょっともう回AとB順番にお願いします！
Please let me taste A and B in order again!
AとBを。
A and B.
うん。なんかね、噛むたびにピリッとした風味が口の中に広がって、めちゃめちゃ美味しい！
Yeah. Every time I chew, a tangy flavor spreads in my mouth, it's super delicious!
やばいあと1分らしい。B、B、B、B、B…
Oh no, only 1 minute left apparently. B, B, B, B, B...
お。うん。なんかとろけるんだよなこれ！
Oh. Yeah. This just melts in my mouth!
美味しいB！食べたい！ちょうだい！
Delicious B! I want to eat it! Give it to me!
あ。うん。わかんない！もうわかんない！
Ah. Yeah. I don't know! I don't know anymore!
もう時間なさそうだから！
There doesn't seem to be much time left!
リリカわかりました。
Lirika understands.
任せてくださいよ。
Just leave it to me.
えっと、値段が安い順でC、A、B。これで提出です！ドヤッ！
Um, in order of lowest price: C, A, B. That is my submission! Ta-da!
正解！
Correct!
いえーい！見たか！
Yay! Did you see that?
リリカはやっぱり味音痴ではないということを！これからも料理系VTuberとして手足が縛られ、
Lirika is indeed not bad at tasting! From now on, as a cooking VTuber with my hands and feet tied,
そして目隠しをされながらも美味しい料理を作っていきたいと思います！おまいまーす！
and while being blindfolded, I want to keep making delicious food! Thank you!
あれ？ボタン押しちゃった
Huh? I pressed the button.
ごめんなさい！
I'm sorry!
ばかやろー！
You idiot!
もっと…ディスゲームなんて…こりごりだ！
I'm sick of games like this...!
次は…みんなに仕返ししてやるからなーっ！
Next time, I'll get my revenge on all of you!
せーの！ReGLOSSです！
Ready, set! We are ReGLOSS!
みんな一緒に楽しんでね！
Let's all have fun together!
行くぞ！
Let's go!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
めくるめく好奇心を身を乗り出そう
行く末絡み添えも知らぬ場所
Leaning into our swirling curiosity,
to places unknown where paths entwine.
街に毛のない情熱が
まっさらぎょーしゃ奏でたトット
Passions burning brightly across the city,
striking up a fresh chord.
寝付きの悪い夜もロクでもない夜も
めまぐるしい時代も全部
Restless nights, good-for-nothing nights,
and this dizzying era—all of it!
傍観の影さえ笑い飛ばそう
Let's laugh away even the shadows of bystanders.
君だ君だ未来なう
You, you, it's the future now!
SUPER DUPER 赤く中空のシャンデリア
SUPER DUPER, a red chandelier in the sky,
出来損でまで踊ろうよ
Let's dance until we can't anymore!
誰が何と言おうと気にしない秘密の会場
No matter what anyone says, our secret venue,
そうだ楽しむだけ 美しい声を響かせて
Yeah, just enjoy it, let your beautiful voice ring out!
うつむいた世界を返してみせよう
Show them we can turn this downcast world around!
SUPER DUPER 焦がそうぜもう自転逆転
たとえ一歩メロディが逆でたって
SUPER DUPER, let's burn it up, reversing rotation,
Even if our melody takes a step backward.
点々としてももう一度ここに乾杯
人生そのものが先性となる万券
Even if scattered, let's toast here once more,
Life itself becomes a pre-ordained victory.
生きながら一躍羽ばたいて去りにな
一番目指し走り出せ
Soaring and leaving while alive,
Running towards the number one spot.
持ち合わせるジェニアス
街中を揺がす猛者様
Armed with genius,
Masters shaking up the town.
浮き足立とうと問題ない
No problem even if we get carried away.
さらけ出した胸の奥愛せやまないもの
疑うことも知らないまま
Loving the depths of our exposed hearts without doubt,
そうひとが描くことはできてるよ
君だ君だ未来なう
Yes, we can draw it ourselves,
You, you, it's the future now!
SUPER DUPER 赤く中空のシャンデリア
SUPER DUPER, a red chandelier in the sky,
出来損でまで踊ろうよ
Let's dance until we can't anymore!
誰が何と言おうと気にしない秘密の会場
No matter what anyone says, our secret venue,
そうだ楽しむだけ 美しい声を響かせて
Yeah, just enjoy it, let your beautiful voice ring out!
うつむいた世界を返してみせよう
Show them we can turn this downcast world around!
SUPER DUPER
生き延びるもっと いちご一会をそそいで
Surviving more, pouring in once-in-a-lifetime encounters,
一心同体でいて
Staying as one body and soul.
こういうの恋したメロディと
With a melody in love with moments like this,
会えなくて話したレプリカ
Replicas talked about when we couldn't meet.
間もなく君との境界線を越えリフレイン
Soon crossing the boundary line with you, refrain!
SUPER DUPER 赤く中空のシャンデリア
SUPER DUPER, a red chandelier in the sky,
出来損でまで踊ろうよ
Let's dance until we can't anymore!
誰が何と言おうと気にしない秘密の会場
No matter what anyone says, our secret venue,
そうだ楽しむだけ 美しい声を響かせて
Yeah, just enjoy it, let your beautiful voice ring out!
うつむいた世界を変えてみせよう
Show them we can change this downcast world!
SUPER DUPER
やったー！
Yay!
ソロパートとユニット曲のSUPER DUPER、楽しんでいただけましたか？
Did you enjoy the solo parts and unit song 'SUPER DUPER'?
青くん感動したよ！
Ao-kun, I was moved!
やめて！
Stop it!
ありがとうございました！ ソロパートとユニット曲「SUPER DUPER」楽しんでいただけましたが
Thank you very much! We hope you enjoyed the solo parts and the unit song 'SUPER DUPER'.
青くん感動したよ！
Ao-kun, I was moved!
やめて！
Stop it!
めちゃめちゃ上手かったよ！
You did amazingly well!
感動したよ！
We were so moved!
僕絶対ホロライブに入って3Dをお披露目する時は絶対歌うって決めてました！
I had decided that the moment I joined Hololive and debuted in 3D, I would definitely sing!
うんうん！
Yeah, yeah!
歌わせていただきありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for letting me sing!
シャンパンも最高だったよ！
The champagne was also the best!
シャンパンコールはオリジナルです！
The champagne call is original!
莉々華ちゃんのもすごかったよ！
Ririka-chan's was amazing too!
今回ですね、撮影にご協力いただきました
This time, for cooperating with our filming...
箱根ガラスの森美術館さん、ポーラ美術館さん、本当にありがとうございました！
Hakone Glass Forest Museum and Pola Museum of Art, thank you so much!
ダンスもめちゃくちゃ可愛かった！
The dance was also super cute!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
リリかさ、お披露目緊張したよね。
Lilika, your debut reveal was so nerve-wracking.
お披露目緊張したデスゲームです、あれ本当に手震ってもらってました！
My debut reveal was like a death game, my hands were literally shaking!
いや、それこそリリカだよ。
Man, that is so Lilika.
じゃあちょっとね、次の曲の準備も… じまちか？
So, um, are we ready for the next song's prep? Chimachi?
そうだね！
That's right!
じゃあマイク取りに…
Let's go get our mics...
マイク、スタンドマイクでっせよ。
Stand mics, you know.
なんだって？
What's that?
それでは次の曲、聞いてください。歌カタメイビー
And now, please listen to our next song: "Utakata Maybe".
嵐のまえみたいな静さ 触れた温度はまだアンニュイ
The calm before the storm,
the touch still feels languid
一喜一憂 過ぎたアウレカ
A roller coaster of emotions,
尽きるまでは冷えない探究心
my curiosity won't cool until it's exhausted
立ち止まれば目の前には 振り返ったときの自分がいて
When I stop, in front of me,
is the self I left behind
小声で呟くシルエット ぼけて何も聞こえない phrase
A silhouette whispers softly,
but it blurs and I hear nothing
泡沫メイビー 回り右、今夜分かれ道
Ephemeral maybe, turning right,
tonight's the crossroads
胸騒ぎレイニー 繰り返し、さよなら溜息
A restless rainy feeling, repeating,
a sigh of goodbye
ほんのちょっとの間の停滞 燻ったままの低体温
A brief stagnation,
with low body temperature smoldering
失った過去も少し手痛い？ 今は見だまだ見過ごしていたいよ
The past I've lost stings a little—
for now, I still want to overlook it
空が白んだって眩しいな たあと一つ何か足りないんだ
The sky brightens, wetting my eyelids—
something is still missing
充電みたいなエブリデイ すべて青天の霹靂
Every day feels like recharging,
everything a bolt from the blue
遠巻きのバイタリティ いつも記憶が愛しいよ
A distant vitality,
always the memories are endearing
変哲のない日々の破片 散らばって立ち往生している
Fragments of ordinary days scattered around,
leaving me stranded
ずっと微風に黄昏れていたいよ 雲隠れした淡い期待
I want to keep being embraced by the gentle breeze,
lost in twilight, fleeting hopes hidden behind clouds
泡沫メイビー 回り右、今夜分かれ道
Ephemeral maybe, turning right,
tonight's the crossroads
胸騒ぎレイニー 繰り返し、さよなら溜息
A restless rainy feeling, repeating,
a sigh of goodbye
痺れるような幕開けをただじっと待っている day & night
Waiting silently for a thrilling new beginning, day and night
雲と雲の切れ間から rays of light shining
Rays of light shining
through the gaps between the clouds
「もう後ろを振り返らないで」
"Don't look back anymore,"
そう呟いたんだ
I whispered to myself.
嵐のまえみたいな静さ 触れた温度はまだアンニュイ
The calm before the storm,
the touch still feels languid
一喜一憂 過ぎたアウレカ 尽きるまでは冷えない探究心
A roller coaster of emotions,
my curiosity won't cool until it's exhausted
立ち止まれば目の前には 振り返ったときの自分がいて
When I stop, in front of me,
is the self I left behind
小声で呟くシルエット ぼけて何も聞こえない phrase
A silhouette whispers softly,
but it blurs and I hear nothing
泡沫メイビー 回り右、今夜分かれ道
Ephemeral maybe, turning right,
tonight's the crossroads
胸騒ぎレイニー 繰り返し、さよなら溜息
A restless rainy feeling, repeating,
a sigh of goodbye
痺れるような幕開けをただじっと待っている day & night
Waiting silently for a thrilling new beginning, day and night
雲と雲の切れ間から rays of light shining
Rays of light shining
through the gaps between the clouds
「もう後ろを振り返らないで」
"Don't look back anymore,"
そう呟いたんだ
I whispered to myself.
大切にとっての大切な曲をアカペラで歌わせていただきます。
I'll be singing a very precious song acapella.
もうあなたから愛されることも
No longer will I be loved by you,
必要とされることもない
nor will I ever be needed again.
そして私はこうして一人ぼっちで
And so I am left here all alone.
あの時あなたは何て言ったの
What was it you said to me back then?
届かない言葉は宙を舞う
The words that won't reach me dance in the air
わかってるのに今日もしてしまう
And though I know better, today too I end up
叶わぬ願い事を
Wishing for things that won't come true
離さないで ぎゅっと手を握っていて
Don't let me go, just squeeze my hand tight
あなたと二人 続くと言って
And tell me we'll go on together, just the two of us
繋いだその手は温かくて
Your hand in mine was warm
優しかった
And gentle
あなたはいつもそうやって私を
That's how you always anger me
怒らせて最後に泣かすんだ
And make me cry in the end
だけど後になってごめんねっていう
But afterwards you'd apologize and say you're sorry
その顔好きだった
I loved the look on your face
離さないで ぎゅっと そう思いっきり
Don't let me go, hold me tight, yes, with all your strength
あなたの腕の中にいたい
I want to be in your arms
二人ででおでこを合わせながら眠るの
We'll fall asleep as we touch our foreheads together
もう二度とは会えないってことを知っていたの?
Did you know that we'd never be able to meet ever again?
離さないで ぎゅっと あなたが好き
Don't let me go, hold me tight, I love you
もう一度だって笑ってくれないの
Won't you laugh for me just one more time?
あなたの温もりが消えちまう前に
Before your warmth vanishes away
抱きしめて
Embrace me
もう一度だって笑ってくれないの
Won't you laugh for me just one more time?
あなたの温もりが消えちまう前に
Before your warmth vanishes away
抱きしめて
Embrace me
遠目で見仰いだ雲の上
Looking up far away above the clouds
ベールに包まれたあの星まで
Up to that star wrapped in a veil
流れ落ちてきた光に跨って
Straddling the light that came falling down
一緒に遊泳飛行しよう
Let's go swimming and flying together
look out 無数の星たちが
Look out, countless stars
鬱々としてステップ刻んでいる
Are gloomily stepping along
我が物顔で招くアイソレーション
An isolation beckoning with a proprietary look
クール決め込む絶対零度
Absolute zero locking in a cool front
凍えない夢にはお愛嬌
Cute charm for a dream that won't freeze
花咲く笑顔が似合いそう
A blooming smile would suit you well
イエローナイトみたいなパラダイソ
A paradise like a yellow night
踊ろうよ under the starlight
Let's dance under the starlight
たったひとりのハーフジャンプ
Just a single half-jump,
キミだけのプレイリストと
And your very own playlist,
マイクフロー耳元まで運ぶよ
Carrying the mic flow right to your ears.
Don't be shy, like it more, don't be shy, like it more
闇を照らすオーロラ
The aurora illuminating the darkness,
言葉いらっつの織り姫
The Weaver Princess who needs no words.
踊ってたいずっと
I want to dance forever,
またとないこの日を降り注ぐプラズマ
Pouring plasma over this once-in-a-lifetime day.
キミがいればPlus one、色濃く映そう、キミとのハイライト
With you, it's plus one, let's vividly reflect our highlight together.
闇付きになるダンス、ハイになるまでアイアイ
A dance you'll get hooked on, eyes locked until we're high.
寝ても覚めても輝くトワイライト
A twilight that shines whether asleep or awake.
きらめいたらNice, nice, まっとう光りアイアイ
Once it sparkles, nice, nice, shining pure, eye eye.
かかりの劇にふっと酔いしれた
Suddenly intoxicated by a fleeting play,
そんな野蛮な季節はとうに過ぎた
Such wild seasons have long since passed.
みんなほっと知らぬくらいが一番ちょうどいい
It's best when everyone hardly knows about it.
甘めにフリル着飾る強欲の日々
Days of greed, dressed up in sweet frills.
続せバラバラのセントウユニティ
Scattered battle unity.
笑い合えたはずの絆ジョイジ
Joyful bonds we should have shared.
寒い心とメロディ、格差パスポートの精度に凍え
Freezing in the precision of a cold heart, melody, and disparity passport.
笑い合った距離さや、切り開け天使、見栄張る栗をね
The distance we laughed together, pave the way, angel, putting on airs...
夢中になっていた頃には
Back when we were engrossed in it,
時は行方を狂わせた
Time threw our whereabouts off course.
幸せ運べ水星が
May the Mercury carrying happiness
オーバーフロー満たしていく世界中
Fill the entire world with overflow.
Don't be shy, like it more, don't be shy, like it more
闇を照らすオーロラ
The aurora illuminating the darkness,
言葉いらっつの織り姫
The Weaver Princess who needs no words.
踊ってたいずっと
I want to dance forever,
またとないこの日を降り注ぐプラズマ
Pouring plasma over this once-in-a-lifetime day.
キミがいればPlus one、色濃く映そう、キミとのハイライト
With you, it's plus one, let's vividly reflect our highlight together.
闇付きになるダンス、ハイになるまでアイアイ
A dance you'll get hooked on, eyes locked until we're high.
寝ても覚めても輝くトワイライト
A twilight that shines whether asleep or awake.
きらめいたらNice, nice, まっとう光りアイアイ
Once it sparkles, nice, nice, shining pure, eye eye.
まっとう光りアイスアイス
Shining pure, ice ice.
姿勢正して ひねくれた態度じゃ 不合格です
Sit up straight, with that twisted attitude, you're failing.
不幸中の幸いは 飽きてしまうわ
The silver lining of misfortune just gets boring.
目を覚まして いい加減な言いなりに
Wake up, blindly following orders half-heartedly—
黙ってうなずいてちゃ no no no 伸び代がないわ
just nodding silently, no no no, you've got no room to grow.
i got 123456 things on my mind
I got 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 things on my mind,
思考一向にまとまんない what do i do
My thoughts won't come together at all, what do I do?
running i'm running away 追いかける yesterday
Running, I'm running away, chasing yesterday.
決める覚悟 迷いは捨て 'cause it's gonna hurt more the longer you wait
Make your resolve, cast away hesitation 'cause it's gonna hurt more the longer you wait.
駆引きなんていらない say whatcha wanna say
No need for playing games, say whatcha wanna say.
憂鬱なマンスリー 気分はブルー 痛みを取り剥がす
Melancholy monthly, feeling blue, biting through the pain and stripping it away.
古びた bandage いらない do whatcha wanna do
Don't need an old bandage, do whatcha wanna do.
情けないね 言い訳ばかり conversation も勘弁
How pathetic, enough with the constant excuses and conversation.
つまずくの恐れちゃ どこも行けないわ
If you're afraid of stumbling, you won't go anywhere.
世は罠ばかり 歯を見せれば見せられる nightmare?
The world is full of traps, bare your teeth and you're shown a nightmare?
無感情になれるなら 教えて頂戴
If you can become emotionless, teach me how.
tell me abcdefg 正解のライン 言葉選び出せない
Tell me ABCDEFG, the correct line, I can't choose my words.
what do i do
finding i'm finding a way 追いかける one more day
Finding, I'm finding a way, chasing one more day.
決める覚悟 迷いは捨て 'cause it's gonna hurt more the longer you wait
Make your resolve, cast away hesitation 'cause it's gonna hurt more the longer you wait.
駆引きなんていらない say whatcha wanna say
No need for playing games, say whatcha wanna say.
憂鬱なマンスリー 気分はブルー 痛みを取り剥がす
Melancholy monthly, feeling blue, biting through the pain and stripping it away.
古びた bandage いらない do whatcha wanna do
Don't need an old bandage, do whatcha wanna do.
また見て見ぬふりの繰り返し ズタボロな心を誰かのせいばかりしたって 何も変わりはしないの
Repeating turning a blind eye over and over, blaming someone else for your battered heart won't change a thing.
負いた傷口も瘡蓋に いつかは剥がれ落ちて
Even the wounds you bore turn to scabs, and one day they'll peel off.
sorry not so sorry 選んだ story 自分次第でしょ
Sorry not so sorry, the story you chose is up to you.
決める覚悟 迷いは捨て 'cause it's gonna hurt more the longer you wait
Make your resolve, cast away hesitation 'cause it's gonna hurt more the longer you wait.
駆引きなんていらない say whatcha wanna say
No need for playing games, say whatcha wanna say.
憂鬱なマンスリー 気分はブルー 痛みを取り剥がす
Melancholy monthly, feeling blue, biting through the pain and stripping it away.
古びた bandage いらない do whatcha wanna do
Don't need an old bandage, do whatcha wanna do.
まだ見ぬセリフの繰り返し ざらついた心を 誰かのせいばかりしたって
Repeating unseen lines, blaming someone else for your jagged heart...
何も変わりはしない
Nothing changes at all.
青い空の中 飛行機雲が 白い線を引いた
In the blue sky, a vapor trail drew a white line.
埋められないが 漂えないが 切ないままが
Though I can't fill it, though I can't drift, staying heartbroken...
あれこれ混ぜて 混ぜてって言ってください
Mix this and that, please tell me to mix them.
いいとこ取って 混ぜて 変えていくだけ のっけに
Taking the good parts, mixing and changing them right away.
僕らニッポンで 4つ打ちで 歪んだ心で行く
We go in Japan with a four-on-the-floor beat and a warped heart.
怯えた目できみを狙うのさ
Targeting you with timid eyes.
きっと何年も経ってもさ 変われないものがある
Surely, even after years, there are things that cannot change.
玉虫の旗を掲げては 胸を張った BANDAGE
Flying the iridescent flag, puffing out my chest, BANDAGE.
空見上げた BANDAGE
Looking up at the sky, BANDAGE.
盛り上がってるかい！？
Are you getting hyped!?
みんなもっともっと大きな声で サブ使ってください！いくぞ！
Everyone, use your biggest voices and sub! Let's go!
ドキドキしようぜ 最高潮 vivids
Let's get our hearts racing at the peak, vivids!
一心同体 誰だってはfavorite
Body and soul as one, whoever you are is your favorite.
ドキドキ このままでいいたいでしょ vivids
Let our hearts race just like this, vivids.
アドレナリンよ everybody!
Adrenaline, hey everybody!
それぞれ異なって カッチこマイナスもプラスになり街は
Different in their own ways, even minuses turn to pluses, and the streets...
妖怪だらけ仲間 景色はバイマイセルフ
Comrades full of specters, the scenery is by my self.
ぶった話まり 時にはバカ騒ぎ
Telling tall tales, sometimes making a ruckus.
運命 共同体 全然して行く気のあいだ
Destiny shared fate, totally going with that feeling in between.
私たちL to M足し 共に目指すわ
Us adding L to M, aiming together.
二度とない Yay! 絶対絶対絶対絶対聞き逃すな
Never again, Yay! Absolutely, absolutely, absolutely don't miss it.
今は自由気まま 水色のユニバース
Right now, freely as we please, the light blue universe.
緑ののりの のりこすシナップス
Green rhythm's surpassing synapse.
限界突破 引き付けるメロディ
Breaking our limits, an attractive melody.
わぁみんな！タップ誓ってくれてありがとね！
Wow everyone! Thanks for tapping along!
次はみんな一緒にワイパー落ちてくよ！
Next, everyone wipaa together!
ドキドキしようぜ 最高潮 vivids
Let's get our hearts racing at the peak, vivids!
一心同体 誰だってはfavorite
Body and soul as one, whoever you are is your favorite.
ドキドキ このままでいいたいでしょ vivids
Let our hearts race just like this, vivids.
アドレナリンよ everybody!
Adrenaline, hey everybody!
片隅のモノローグも 繋がるプライベートモモ
Even the monologue in the corner connects to our private moments.
手術があっという間のひとり みんなといる空間がエクストリー
Surgery passing in a flash alone, the space with everyone is extreme.
予断する余暇がないメモリーじゃに 胸に掴み取るネクストリーン
Memories with no spare time to idle, grasping the next green in my chest.
運命 共同体 全然して行く気のあいだ
Destiny shared fate, totally going with that feeling in between.
二度とない Yay! 絶対絶対絶対絶対聞き逃すな
Never again, Yay! Absolutely, absolutely, absolutely don't miss it.
今は自由気まま 水色のユニバース
Right now, freely as we please, the light blue universe.
緑ののりの のりこすシナップス
Green rhythm's surpassing synapse.
限界突破 引き付けるミラコー
Breaking our limits, an attractive miracle.
ドキドキしようぜ 最高潮 vivids
Let's get our hearts racing at the peak, vivids!
一心同体 誰だってはfavorite
Body and soul as one, whoever you are is your favorite.
ドキドキ このままでいいたいでしょ vivids
Let our hearts race just like this, vivids.
アドレナリンよ everybody!
Adrenaline, hey everybody!
やったー！すごい楽しかったね！
Yay! That was so much fun!
一気に気がしたね。ソロパートからのね二人の曲。
That really hit us. From solo parts to the two-person song.
それからバリィズもありましたが、ね。
And then there was barīzu too, right.
カナデ赤ペラシビれたよ～！めっちゃめちゃよかったよ！
Kanade, your acapella gave me chills~! It was so, so good!
泣きそうになった。変わって貰えてうれしーね。
I almost cried. I'm so happy you got to switch.
動きがうるさい！そんなことないよ！
Your movements are noisy! No they aren't!
レベルがちげえ。これめちゃ好き。
The level is totally different. I love this so much.
これこれこれ！こういうやつ！違う違う違う！
This, this, this! This kind of thing! No no no!
ありがとね、みんなでねバリィズも歌って。
Thank you, everyone sang barīzu together too.
バリィズも歌って楽しかったにゃ。
It was so fun singing barīzu too.
コメント欄もみんなすごい！めっちゃカナデとかバーチョとかリカーとかアオくんとかラデとかみんな
The comment section is amazing too! Everyone saying Kanade, Bacho, Rika, Ao-kun, Rade, everyone...
ねぇねぇ見えてる？え？
"Hey, hey, can you see us? Huh?"
聞こえてる？
"Can you hear us?"
なんか、きのこって言ってるの見えてる？
"Can you see people saying 'mushroom'?"
ありがとうございます！
"Thank you!"
ワンチャンこっちがきのこかも知れん。見てこの帽子。あ、確かに！
"Maybe we're the mushrooms. Look at this hat." "Ah, true!"
やめろ！
"Stop it!"
エノキ！そっちで？エノキ？エノキ？
"Enoki! Over there? Enoki? Enoki?"
エノキ？
"Enoki?"
後ろ！後ろ！
"Behind you! Behind you!"
え、ちょっとさ、せっかくだからさ、みんなさ、くるくるって回転してさ、後ろも見てもらおうよ。
"Since we're all here, let's spin around so everyone can see the back too."
いいよ、せーの。
"Sure, ready, go."
行くよ。もう回っちゃった。もう回っちゃった。せいら、せーの！いいね。
"Here we go. You already spun. You already spun. Seira, ready, go! Nice."
こんな感じになってます。
"That's how it looks."
イェーイ！イェーイ！ありがとうございますみなさん！
"Yay! Yay! Thank you everyone!"
はい、というわけで、残すところあと1曲なんですが、
"Yes, so, there is only one song left, but..."
まだ来たばっかり！
"We just got here!"
終わったあとにですね、終わったあと21時30分からデバイス公式チャンネルのメンバーシップ限定でアンコールライブがありますので、
"After it ends, starting at 21:30, there will be an encore live exclusive to the Device official channel membership,"
見たい方は今のうちにメンバーシップの登録をぜひお願いいたします！お願いしまーす！お願いしまーす！
"so if you want to watch, please register for the membership now! Please do! Please do!"
えー、私たちのチャンネルのメンバーシップ、私達個人のですね、
"Um, for our channel membership, our individual ones..."
チャンネルのメンバーシップでは推しカメラ配信もございますので、ぜひ6窓で見ていただければと思います！よろしくおねがいします！お願いします！
"There will also be oshi-camera streams, so we hope you'll watch with multi-view! Thank you very much! Please!"
お願いします！アンコールライブはこの今立っているアリーナじゃない別のステージ！
"Please! The encore live will be on a different stage, not this arena we're standing in!"
私たちにゆかりのあるところと言えば？
"Speaking of somewhere connected to us..."
オレンジ！オレンジ！オレンジ！オレンジ！
"Orange! Orange! Orange! Orange!"
ね、着替えて、そのパートのときの衣装での配信となります。
"Right, we'll change clothes and stream in the outfits from that part."
裏話とか感想なんかもちょっとゆっくりね、話す機会もあるかなといったところでございますので、楽しみにしていてください！
"There will also be time to slowly talk about behind-the-scenes stories and impressions, so please look forward to it!"
え、ここで告知情報になります！かなでよろしく！
"Now, here is some announcement info! Kanade, please!"
ファーストアルバム『ReGLOSS』2024年11月6日に発売される私たちのファーストアルバム『ReGLOSS』が絶賛予約受付中です！
"Our 1st album 'ReGLOSS', releasing on November 6, 2024, is currently available for pre-order!"
全国流通盤は初回プレス限定封入特典としてランダムミニカードが1枚入っているのですが、ミニカードの絵柄はこちらとなっております！
"The nationwide distribution version includes one random mini-card as a first-press limited enclosure bonus, and the designs are right here!"
こちらで！
"Right here!"
じゃじゃーん！
"Ta-da!"
こちら！
"Here!"
お哦、可愛い！可愛い！
"Oh, cute! Cute!"
各販売店にてお買い求めいただけますので、詳細は各販売店さんのサイトをご確認ください！
"You can purchase them at various retailers, so please check each retailer's site for details!"
さらに、ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップにて通常版の販売が決定いたしました！イェーイ！
"Furthermore, the regular edition will be sold at the hololive production official shop! Yay!"
こちらは特典で、アニ...アニャ...アニャジャケット？アニバーサリー？アナザージャケット、アナザージャケットです！
"This comes with a bonus, an ani... Anya... Anya jacket? Anniversary? Another jacket, another jacket!"
本日21時より販売開始となりますので、詳細は、販売ページをご確...確認ください！
"Sales will start today at 21:00, so please check the sales page for details!"
そして、はい！僕たちの3Dアクリルスタンドが出まーす！
"And, yes! Our 3D acrylic stands are coming out!"
ぜひね、5人並べて飾ってってください、こんな感じでポンポンポンポンってね。
"Please line up all five of them and display them like this, boom boom boom."
はい！さらに、今回の3Dライブを記念してグッズが販売されまーす！
"Yes! Furthermore, merchandise commemorating this 3D live will be sold!"
可愛い！
"So cute!"
まずは、こちら！僕たち5人の直筆のコメントがプリントされたリボンタイプのストラップです！
"First, this! A ribbon-type strap printed with handwritten comments from all five of us!"
そしてこちら！アクリルフォトフレームと5人の複製箔押しサイン入りのブロマイドです！
"And this! An acrylic photo frame and a bromide with duplicated foil-stamped signatures of the five."
以上！すげえたまらなかった！
"That's all! So amazing!"
公式オンラインショップで21時からお求めいただけます！
"You can purchase them on the official online shop starting at 21:00!"
でもですね、皆さん、今回は数量限定などではないので、皆さん焦らずに最後までこのライブを見てから買って下さいね！よろしくお願いします！
"However, everyone, this time it's not quantity-limited, so don't rush and please watch this live to the end before buying! Thank you!"
そして！9月27日よりReGLOSS活動1周年記念ボイスが絶賛発売中です！
"And! ReGLOSS 1st Anniversary Voice is now on sale starting September 27!"
イェーイ！可愛い！かっこいい！かっこよすぎる！
"Yay! So cute! So cool! Too cool!"
ね、結成当時のよそ行き描いたボイスドラマとボイスメッセージ風シチュエーションボイスをぜひぜひお楽しみにしてください！
"Please look forward to the voice drama depicting our formal times back when we formed and the voice message-style situation voices!"
はい、そして、10月10日に3Dライブ振り返りの3D配信を実施します！
"Yes, and on October 10, we will hold a 3D stream looking back at the 3D live!"
え、次回の3D配信10月10日にお会いいたしましょう。お楽しみに！
"Um, let's meet on October 10 for the next 3D stream. Look forward to it!"
告知も盛りだくさんだったんですけど、
"There were lots of announcements too, but..."
え、まだね、皆さん最後の曲聞いてないですよね？こないだリリースした新曲聴きたいよね？
"Um, you guys haven't heard the last song yet, right? You want to hear the new song we released recently, right?"
じゃあみんなで1日注いで最後の曲行こう！うおおお！
"Then let's all pour into it and go to the final song! Whoa!"
Long hard days 気分はどう？
Long hard days, how are you feeling?
日々の鬱屈とした心情
The gloomy feelings of everyday life,
さあ 回り道して Show Time
Come on, take a detour for Show Time.
全然悪くない マジェスティーション
It's not bad at all, manifestation.
誓いのキリは晴れ渡って
The mist of the oath clears up,
悲しみには枯れを告げる
And bids farewell to sorrow.
スイミング マイム もうちょいほり出して
Swimming mime, dig a little deeper,
滲むソーダインクのパラダイム
A paradigm of bleeding soda ink.
どれだけうまく見せようとしても
No matter how well I try to show it,
君がいなければなんの意味もない
It means nothing if you aren't here.
かすり傷すらつかない幻想
An illusion where not even a scratch is left,
針の落ちないレコードさ
A record where the needle won't drop.
灰色まとめとない良い風説にして
Turning it into a decent rumor...
飛び乗って The Future
Jump on, The Future!
ライン引いて オレに Start line
Draw the line, to my Start line.
遠く決めてしまえば
If we decide far ahead,
またたく間に広がる解放区
A liberated zone spreads in the blink of an eye.
人びと すべてがドラマ
People and all, everything is a drama.
街は見た目で Start line
The city, by appearance, is a Start line.
かわるがわるよ ドラマ
Changing one after another, a drama.
道あふれる フィーリンググラデーション
Overflowing roads, feeling gradation.
始まりのその時が来た
The time of beginning has come.
ナスにジップシッポ
With a neat zip and tail...
目まぐるしくおかし気から世界
A dizzying, strangely changing world,
この先はまだ誰も知らない世界
A world ahead that no one knows yet.
傍観してるだけじゃ味わえない
You can't experience it just by standing by.
リアルタイムで通じ合って
Connecting in real time.
フリックにがけるモーション
A motion drawn with a flick,
後のお祭りでもアンドマインド
Even as an after-party, and mind.
大体素敵なシチュエーション
Mostly a wonderful situation.
行けるところまで行ってみたい
I want to go as far as I can.
素肌を貫くような真っ直ぐな痛みが
A straight pain that pierces the bare skin
伴ってもの仲間たちと最果てまで
With my companions, to the farthest end.
飛び乗って The Future
Jump on, The Future!
ライン引いて オレに Start line
Draw the line, to my Start line.
遠く決めてしまえば
If we decide far ahead,
またたく間に広がる解放区
A liberated zone spreads in the blink of an eye.
人びと すべてがドラマ
People and all, everything is a drama.
街は見た目で Start line
The city, by appearance, is a Start line.
かわるがわるよ ドラマ
Changing one after another, a drama.
道あふれる フィーリンググラデーション
Overflowing roads, feeling gradation.
飛び出せ You raise me up
Jump out, You raise me up.
恐れるものは何もない Start line
Nothing to fear on the Start line.
綺麗な朝焼けが
The beautiful morning glow
透明な明日を照らすよ
Illuminates a transparent tomorrow.
Reset to life